Preliminary Inventory to the Dumitru Danielopol Papers, 1940-1973
Hoover Institution Archives
Dumitru Danielopol Papers,
1940-1973
72047
Danielopol, Dumitru
10 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope. (4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, writings, reports, and photographs, relating to the Paris Peace Conference, 1946, the peace settlement with Romania at the end of World War II, and world politics, 1943-1973.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
Paris Peace Conference (1946); Communism.; World politics.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Peace.; World War, 1939-1945--Romania.; Romania.; Romania--Politics and government--1944-1989.; Romanians--United States.; United States.
Container List
General Topics
- After Paris (magazine clipping, October 18, 1946) (Box 1)
- British Broadcasting Corporation
- Conference de Paris. Palais du Luxembourg. 29 Juillet 1946.
- Contre Offensive de Paix by Grigoire Gafencu, 1953
- George Danielopol
- Economic Development in S. E. Europe
- England - war time press, 1940-44
- England - war time press, King Michael's abdication, 1947
- Malaxa group and King Michael's friends
- Malaxa group and King Michael's friends (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
- Obervations Concerning the Draft Peace Treaty with Rumania
- Peace Treaty manuscript
- Pre-war material
- Radio Free Europe, 1950-53
- Romanian News Survey, London, August 1943-August 1944 (Box 3)
- Romanii din Londra in al doilea rasboiu mondial
- Roumania at the Peace Conference, Paris
- War-time material
- Draft Peace Treaty With Roumania, Paris, July 18, 1946
Increment 1975 (April): Articles Written for Copley Newspapers, 1964-1973
- Absent-Minded Prof, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), March 14, 1969 (Box 4)
- Actress Has Same Aim as McCarthy, Daily News-Post (Monrovia, Calif.), January 2, 1968
- Administration Has Misjudged Nature Aims of Communists, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 11, 1968
- Ambitious Publisher - Win Touches Off Alarm, Elgin Daily Courier- News (Illinois), July 20, 1970
- America: Greatest Country - 'Delayed Pilgrim' Ashamed of Current Attitudes, The San Diego Union (Calif.), November 6, 1967
- American Achievements Recognized World-Wide, The San Diego Union (Calif.), January 6, 1969
- American People Are Entitled to Facts About Peace Marches, Aurora News (Illinois), December 5, 1967
- Americans Are Beginning to Awaken, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 22, 1964
- Americans Find Friends in Tunisia, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), June 27, 1967
- Analyst Says Our Prestige at Record Low, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), March 27, 1968
- Angry Ethnic Rhetoric Expected, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 7, 1972
- Another Castro in South Viet Nam?, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), May 13, 1966
- Another New Map of South Europe, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), January 25, 1972
- Another 'Nyet' From the Kremlin, San Pedro News-Pilot (Calif.), November 2, 1966
- Answer to Agronsky's Blast, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), May 13, 1970
- Anti-Communist Exiles Don't Feel Lonely Anymore, Aurora-Beacon-News (Illinois), June 16, 1969
- Anti-Viet War Clamor Red Inspired - Validity of Demonstrations Questioned, Springfield State Journal (Illinois), May 5, 1967
- Anti-War Sentiment in U.S. Troubles Britain, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 7, 1970
- Apathy of Their Victims is Key to Communist Success, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), February 20, 1968
- Appeal to America's Silent, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), January 16, 1970
- Appeasement Puzzles GI's, San Pedro News-Pilot (Calif.), February 22, 1967
- Apollo Feat Blow to Reds, Illinois State Journal, August 9, 1969
- Arms Limit Talks Rouse Optimism, The San Diego Union (Calif.), June 4, 1970
- Army Goal of Warsaw Pact Chief, The San Diego Union (Calif.), February 26, 1970
- As Others See Us - Even Our Friends Are Worried About Us, South Bay Daily Breeze (Torrance, Calif.), December 25, 1968
- Ask Heath If Cold War Is Over, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), April 6, 1972
- Aussie General Voices Concern, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), April 14, 1972
- Austria Neutral on West's Side, The San Diego Union (Calif.), June 29, 1969
- Ballots to Select Italian Leader - President Owes Reds Nothing, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), January 7, 1972
- Berlin Streets Stir Grim Memories, The San Diego Union (Calif.) July 28, 1970
- Bible Stock Misused - Roumanians Propaganda Victims, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), April 3, 1972
- Birthday Party Hints Communism Slipping, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), November 26, 1967
- Bonn Pact Tramples on Rights, The San Diego Union (Calif.), June 4, 1972
- Brainwashing Back in News, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 27, 1967
- Brandts' Moves Worry Europe, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 11, 1970
- Brezhnev Doctrine Saps Czech Spirit, Economy, The San Diego Union (Calif.), January 20, 1970
- Brezhnev's Theory Alarms World, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), December 11, 1968
- Britain's Illusions on Reds Compared With U.S. Policy, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 31, 1964
- British Press Attacks on Goldwater Ironic, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 8, 1964
- British Reverse Attack Now Praise Goldwater, The San Diego Union (Calif.), September 5, 1964
- British Tragedy in Last Act, Illinois State Journal, December 16, 1967
- British Warn of Traps for Visitors in Red Lands, The San Diego Union (Calif.), April 17, 1969
- Briton Gains Through Support of U.S. Policy, Illinois State Journal, July 10, 1965
- Bulgaria Boasts of Aid to North Vietnamese, The San Diego Union (Calif.), September 12, 1966
- Can Democracy Survive?, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), January 21, 1970
- Can Nixon Ease Romania's Pain?, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 27, 1969
- Can Russian Regime Be Destroyed?, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 23, 1966
- Can We Afford Luxury of Olympic Games?, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 17, 1972
- Captive Nations Week Has Become a Farce, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 29, 1972
- Captive Nations Week Has Lessons for Us, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), July 19, 1967
- Captive Nations Parley Sees Little U.S. Help, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 7, 1964
- The Case of Romania - 'Bridges' Built on Shaky Spans, South Bay Daily Breeze (Torrance, Calif.), July 4, 1968
- Castro Still Poses Threat to America, The San Diego Union (Calif.), June 7, 1964
- Caveant Consules, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), April 29, 1970
- Caveat Emptor Still Timely, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), June 20, 1970
- Ceausescu Has His Troubles, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 24, 1969
- A Challenge Renewed - Exiles Refuse to Give Up, South Bay Daily Breeze (Torrance, Calif.), September 10, 1972
- Charles De Gaulle Discovers France Has Short Memory, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 3, 1969
- China Trip Worries Anti-Communist Group, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), December 10, 1971
- China's Cultural Revolution Has Spilled Over in Albania, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), April 8, 1968
- Church a Tool of Government, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), July 23, 1972
- Cold War Getting Colder, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), March 29, 1970
- Coming Home to Roost, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), April 21, 1970
- Commentator Rips TV, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), March 24, 1970
- Commies Still Break Promises, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 5, 1972
- Communism Attacked on Own Soil, San Pedro News-Pilot (Calif.), October 12, 1966
- Communist Countries Have Youth Problems Too, The San Diego Union (Calif.), June 5, 1966
- Communist Problems, Too - Alcoholism, Crime Rate Increasing in Russia, The San Diego Union (Calif.), January 8, 1967
- Communist Propaganda Has Grip on Europeans, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 9, 1970
- Communist Propaganda Staggers Imagination, The San Diego Union (Calif.), September 8, 1965
- Communist Romanian Economy Faces Crisis, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 27, 1968
- Communist Will Be Next President of U.N. Assembly, The San Diego Union (Calif.), April 15, 1967
- Communists: A Total Lack of Morality, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 30, 1964
- Communists Exploit Religion, Glendale News-Press (Calif.), November 22, 1967
- Communists Stretch the Truth, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), January 24, 1967
- Communists Work Hard to Discredit Capitalism, The San Diego Union (Calif.), January 7, 1970
- Communists-on-Campus Seek Only to Brainwash, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 3, 1964
- Constantine Failed Because People Weren't Interested, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), December 27, 1967
- Copper Scrap Shipment to Yugoslavia Protested, The San Diego Union (Calif.), March 12, 1968
- A Correct Mao Thought, Illinois State Journal, September 13, 1969
- Credentials Are Important, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), September 29, 1966
- The 'Crisis' in Confidence, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), October 28, 1967
- Crisis in Soviet Agriculture, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), October 10, 1969
- Croisette's Memorable Vignettes, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), June 6, 1970
- Cuba Seeks to Discredit Church, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 8, 1966
- Cultural Exchanges Just Won't Work, The San Diego Union (Calif.), January 27, 1965
- Cultural Revolution Has Backfired on Mao, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), February 11, 1970
- Czech Issue Puts Russia Over Barrel, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), July 30, 1968
- Czech Liberalization Ends With Soviet Liquidation Job, Illinois State Journal, October 11, 1968
- Czechs' Tragic History, Illinois State Journal, August 30, 1969
- Defend Europe? We Let Reds Take Over in Cuba., The San Diego Union (Calif.), November 30, 1964
- De Gaulle Boosts French Reds, Burbank Daily Review (Calif.), March 28, 1967
- De Gaulle Ignore Own Advice, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), December 7, 1967
- De Gaulle Tries To Discredit Everything That Is American, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), March 12, 1968
- De Gaulle's Decision on NATO Unpopular With Most French, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), May 6, 1966
- De Gaulle's Finest Hour Will Be Remembered Long, The San Diego Union (California), May 8, 1969
- De Gaulle's Tactics Boomerang, Culver City Evening Vanguard (Calif.), November 22, 1966
- Debt of Gratitude Owed Bob Hope, The San Diego Union (Calif.), March 16, 1966
- Dej, Red Boss, Died a Christian, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), May 11, 1966
- Demise of Novotny Was Overdue, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), January 17, 1968
- Democrat Slogan Does Not Admit U.S. Failures, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 29, 1964
- Democrats Uneasy Despite Polls, The San Diego Union (Calif.), September 3, 1964
- Derwinski Puts It Straight to Soviets, The San Diego Union (Calif.), December 6, 1971
- Developing Nations - Financial Aid Fails to Help Countries, South Bay Daily Breeze (Torrance, Calif.), September 28, 1972
- Devil's Children - When a Communist Isn't, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), February 18, 1969
- Displays of Support Give GIs Their Due, Elgin Courier-News (Illinois), November 2, 1967
- Dissent From Dissent Arouses Little Interest, The San Diego Union (Calif.), January 27, 1969
- Dissent or Treason? Youth is Confused, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), November 5, 1969
- Double Standard Seen on Communism, The San Diego Union (Calif.), November 16, 1966
- Doves' Monster Will Haunt Us, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), February 15, 1972
- Drawing Up Balance Sheet of 50 Years of Communism, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 28, 1967
- Dubcek Seen As a Soviet Put Up Job, South Bay Daily Breeze (Torrance, Calif.), June 15, 1969
- Dumitru Danielopol Attending Third Paris Peace Conference, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 4, 1968
- Eartha Kitt Was Tactless, But She Did Have a Point, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), January 29, 1968
- East Europe Looks to U.S., The Sacramento Union (Calif.), April 20, 1968
- Echoes From Bay of Pigs, Illinois State Journal, May 6, 1969
- Ending Vietnam War 'Simple', San Pedro News-Pilot (Calif.), March 20, 1967
- Enemy Can Win in Washington, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), April 1, 1968
- Ethnic Groups Swinging to Republic Side, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 31, 1972
- Ethnics Won't Go For McGovern Line, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), October 23, 1972
- Europe Pleased With Nixon, Illinois State Journal, June 14, 1969
- Europe, Too, Having Troubles Keeping Young People on Farms, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), September 28, 1966
- Europe's View of Kennedy, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), July 2, 1969
- European Exile Leader Hits Western Aid to Red Nations, Evening Tribune (San Diego, Calif.), December 18, 1964
- Europeans Are Puzzled by American Foreign Policy, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 21, 1966
- Europeans Link Campus Riots With Communism, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 7, 1970
- Europeans Understand U.S. Move, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 18, 1970
- Everybody Thinks He's Expert in Field of Foreign Affairs, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), November 23, 1967
- Evidence is There, But Fulbright Won't Listen, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 21, 1969
- Ex-King, Reds Irony Seen in Romanian U.S. Arrivals, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 8, 1964
- Exiles in Spain Show How To Carry On Propaganda Behind the Iron Curtain, Illinois State Register, September 19, 1969
- Fact(?) Finding Missions - The Party Releases the News, South Bay Daily Breeze (Torrance, Calif.), January 10, 1967
- Failure of Liberalism of 60's, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), April 14, 1970
- Failure of Red Agriculture Adds to World Food Shortage, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), May 6, 1968
- Fate Has Part in Friendly Handshake, The San Diego Union (Calif.), October 7, 1968
- Financing Red Bankruptcies, Burbank Daily Review (Calif.), August 5, 1967
- First Appraisal in 1969 Still Stands, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), October 29, 1972
- Flood-Stricken Romania Needs Aid, The San Diego Union (Calif.), June 10, 1970
- Foreign Allies Fear Democrat Nominee, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 19, 1972
- Foreign Diplomats Misinterpret America - Bad to Stay Too Long in East, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), April 26, 1965
- Foreign Policy Gap Needs Attention, The San Diego Union (Calif.), November 7, 1968
- Former French Official Says U.S. Soft on Hanoi, The San Diego Union (Calif.), February 16, 1972
- Former Johnson Aide Debunks Some Myths About Communism, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 12, 1969
- Fostering Appeasement Plays Into Red's Hands, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 9, 1965
- Free World Envoys Like GOP Ticket, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 23, 1968
- Freeing Reds' Captives Called Danger By Some, The San Diego Union (Calif.), December 4, 1964
- French Business Being Hurt, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), July 14, 1966
- French Stand Tests Patience, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), April 11, 1968
- Frenchmen Also Irked By TV Bias - Not Only American Tempers Frayed, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), May 8, 1970
- From Russian Side - Cold War Going Great, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), July 13, 1970
- Fulbright Not Loved Abroad, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), May 24, 1972 (Box 5)
- Fulbright Now After Voice of America, The San Diego Union (Calif.), April 27, 1972
- Fulbright Recalls Muggeridge Theory, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), February 29, 1972
- Fulbright Scare Tactics Long Used By Reds, The San Diego Union (Calif.), September 16, 1964
- Giscardiens Back De Gaulle, Criticize Actions of U.S., Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), July 3, 1967
- General Walt Says War Protests Delayed End, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), October 10, 1969
- Glory That Was Greece, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), March 22, 1968
- Goldwater Denounces Critics of President, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 4, 1972
- Goldwater is Newest Sensation in London, The San Diego Union (Calif.), August 15, 1964
- Goldwaterites Still Determined - Liberal Republicans Could Be Wrong, The San Pedro News-Pilot (Calif.), December 7, 1964
- GOP Dedication - Hope Offered Captive Nations, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 17, 1964
- GOP Guns Poised - Demo Foreign Policy Ammo Smolders, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), August 6, 1968
- Greece - Friend In Need, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), April 25, 1968
- Greek Colonels Impatient With United States Policy, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 18, 1969
- Greek Government Takes Firmer Hold, Elgin Courier-News (Illinois), May 28, 1968
- Greek Newsmen Cite Red Putsch Plan, Springfield State Journal (Illinois), May 12, 1967
- Greek Official Says Greece Isn't Getting a Fair Shake, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), May 30, 1968
- Greek Students Go To School For Education, Not Politics, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 19, 1969
- The Greeks Aren't Gullible, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), July 22, 1966
- Greeks Fear That Washington May Forget 'Truman Doctrine', Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 21, 1967
- Greeks Misrepresented By the 'Liberal Pres', The San Diego Union (Illinois), May 26, 1970
- Grim Picture in Vietnam - Paper Debunks Peace Theory, Illinois State Journal, March 6, 1968
- Grinding Heel of Communism, The San Diego Union (Calif.), July 18, 1984
- Hanoi Could Say Thanks Once More, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), February 22, 1970
- Hanoi's Line on the War, The Sacramento Union (Calif.), July 1, 1968
- 'Hashish Trail' on a Grim Road, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), November 9, 1972
- Heavy Smog of Unreality Blankets Nation's Capital, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), July 28, 1969
- He Does Moscow's Dirty Work, The San Diego Union (Illinois), June 12, 1972
- Heard on Radio Liberty, Aurora Beacon-News (Illionis), April 14, 1972
- Helsinki May Be Picked as Site For Arms Talk by U.S., Russia, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 25, 1969
- Here Are Facts of Life About East-West Trade, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), May 29, 1967
- Here's a Study in Contrasts, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), June 15, 1966
- Here's That Man Again - Tri Quang, the Red Buddhist, South Bay Daily Breeze (Torrance, Calif.), June 10, 1966
- Hess Case Reveals Red Humanitarianism, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), February 6, 1970
- Ho Won French War in Paris, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), October 22, 1967
- The Hope For Meaningful Discussion - Nixon Holds Birds'-Eye View of Russian Confrontation, Illinois State Journal, February 8, 1968
- Ho's Death Raises Vietnam Questions, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), September 9, 1969
- Hospitable Swiss Have Immigration Worries, The San Diego Union (Calif.)
- How Deep Is Rift Between Soviet Union and Romania, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), March 19, 1968
- How Independent is Romanian Satellite?, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), March 31, 1972
- How's Life Under Mao?, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), March 5, 1972
- HHH Didn't Tell Whole Story, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), January 19, 1968
- Humphrey Proposes End to U.S. Peace-Keeping, The San Diego Union (Calif), September 23, 1964
- Hungary Committing Suicide as Nation, The San Diego Union November 9, 1966
- If You're Tempted, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), November 13, 1969
- Ignored By West - Struggle Continues in Eastern Europe, Elgin Courier-News (Illinois), June 24, 1972
- In Perilous Times Nation Needs Voice of Reason, The San Diego Union (Calif.), May 1, 1968
- Indications Red China is Losing Some UN Backers of Last Year, Joliet Herald-News (Illinois), September 27, 1966
- Indochina Record of Reds Alarming, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), March 13, 1972
- Injustice Enforces Authority, Aurora Beacon-News (Illinois), May 18, 1966
- Interesting Promises - Mr. Humphrey's Poor Arithmetic, The Post Advocate (Alhambra, Calif.), January 21, 1972
- International Scene - America's Other Face, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), May 1, 1970
- International Scene - Anti-Semitism on Rise, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), August 7, 1970
- International Scene - Belgrade Lives It Up, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), May 22, 1970
- International Scene - A Blush on Red Faces, Elgin Daily Courier- News (Illinois), March 8, 1965
- International Scene - Another Red Hoax, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), August 5, 1967
- International Scene - Bridge Building Delayed, Elgin Daily Courier- News (Illinois), October 24, 1968
- International Scene - Calls for Peace Ignore Hard Facts, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), March 16, 1967
- International Scene - Campaign Gets Sillier, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), October 28, 1968
- International Scene - Can Russia Afford It?, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), July 8, 1967
- International Scene - Case for United Nations, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), October 2, 1968
- International Scene - Cheers For a Change, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), April 1, 1970
- International Scene - China Jars Red World, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), January 28, 1967
- International Scene - Choice of Nixon Cheered in Europe, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), August 27, 1968
- International Scene - Communism Shows Its Fear of Change, Elgin Daily Courier News (Illinois), April 22, 1967
- International Scene - Communism Won't Feed Hungry World, Elgin Daily Courier News (Illinois), May 1, 1967
- International Scene - Communists Keep Trying, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), July 14, 1965
- International Scene - Corner for the Kremlin, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), February 20, 1969
- International Scene - Corruption Not nice, But it's Fact of Life, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), February 5, 1968
- International Scene - Court Case Stirs Greece Elections, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), April 24, 1967
- International Scene - Date: March 15, 1919, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), March 10, 1969
- International Scene - De Gaulle Loses Grip, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), May 16, 1967
- International Scene - Don't They Have Voice?, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), May 2, 1970
- International Scene - East-West Trade Has Too Many Obstacles, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), May 5, 1967
- International Scene - An Election Sidelight?, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), September 28, 1968
- International Scene - European Journalist Want Trial of Reds, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), June 1, 1967
- International Scene - Ex-Minister Views Sorbonne Turmoil, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), June 10, 1968
- International Scene - Exiled Priest Says America Last Hope, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), August 21, 1967
- International Scene - A Few Snags For Tito, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), February 24, 1970
- International Scene - French Communists Become Ballot Issue, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), March 3, 1967
- International Scene - Frustrated British Take It Out On U.S., Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), May 8, 1967
- International Scene - Greek Denies Torture, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), March 6, 1970
- International Scene - Greeks Grateful to Truman, U.S., Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), April 10, 1967
- International Scene - Growing Crops Just One Russia Problem, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), October 16, 1966
- International Scene - Hanoi Pushes Hard to Win the Peace, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), August 24, 1967
- International Scene - How Vital Is Treaty?, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), October 25, 1968
- International Scene - How Would You Like to Be a Vietnamese? Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), October 3, 1967
- International Scene - Is This Trip Necessary?, Elgin Daily Courier-News (Illinois), December 18, 1968